# Jamie Pantazi Esmond

I am a graduate student at Georgia State University in the Andrew Young School of Policy Studies. I previously worked in the Family Detention Department of RAICES, analyzing and organizing data collected from our detained clients. I am passionate about research, data, and advocacy. I have experience working with issues such as housing insecurity, prison abolition, and peer-led mental health support. I hope to continue my work using data to advocate for marginalized communities struggling against systemic oppression.

1609 Line St. Apt B2 Decatur, GA 30032

(904) 742-7662

jamie.pantazi@gmail.com jesmond1@student.gsu.edu

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Georgia State University,** Atlanta, GA— Graduate Research Assistant/Teaching Assistant/Student

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

Conducted research and organized data for large projects. Utilized coding, including automation, for large data collection. Completed independent research utilizing multiple methods and software. Supported student discussion and understanding of concepts. Maintained a 4.0 GPA.

# **RAICES, Family Detention Department,** San Antonio, TX— Data Analysis Unit Coordinator

JANUARY 2019 - JANUARY 2022

Organized and analyzed data regarding detained clients quickly and without error. Wrote reports on the data and flagged urgent cases when needed. Collected and presented data, sometimes on very short notice. Organized and delegated work for larger projects. Trained others for accurate data collection, entry, and reporting.

## **Icarus Project**, Atlanta, GA — Facilitator

JANUARY 2015 - OCTOBER 2016

Organized, promoted, and led a radical mental health support group. Free and open to all, this organization provided peer support for anyone struggling with any kind of mental health issues or concerns.

## **EDUCATION**

## Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA— Bachelor of Arts History

JANUARY 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

Maintained 4.0 GPA, summa cum laude graduate, Phi Alpha Theta President.

## **Georgia State University,** Atlanta, GA— Master of Public Policy

JANUARY 2022 - DECEMBER 2023

Concentration in policy analytics, maintained 4.0 GPA, held a graduate research assistantship and a teaching assistantship.

### **PROJECTS**

Karnes Family Immigration Prison as an Adult Immigration Prison: Why Expedited Removal and Immigrant Detention Must End — July 2022

#### **SKILLS**

Research and analysis

Critical thinking

Attention to detail

Organization and time management

Data presentation and report writing

Written and oral communication

Data-driven impact evaluation

GIS / STATA / R

Microsoft Office / Google Suite

Passion for helping others

### **AWARDS**

Henry Thompson Malone Memorial Scholarship - 2018

Michael Mescon Public Service Leadership Scholarship - 2022

#### **REFERENCES**

Dr. Gina Caison, Department of English, Georgia State University

Andrea Meza, formerly RAICES

Emeline Renz, Urban Studies Institute, Georgia State University